<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Solar on recursivewit</title>
    <link>http://recursivew.it/tags/solar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Solar on recursivewit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 18:20:18 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://recursivew.it/tags/solar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk Top Secret Tesla Plan</title>
      <link>http://recursivew.it/relay/elon-musk-top-secret-tesla-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 18:20:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://recursivew.it/relay/elon-musk-top-secret-tesla-plan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After catching flak for wanting to buy Solar City with Tesla money, Elon Musk claims to have a top secret Tesla master plan he hopes to release soon. Since news broke up the Solar City acquisition and the investor blowback, I&amp;rsquo;ve said the investors are missing the forest for the trees by getting pissy about it. Anyone who&amp;rsquo;s watched Musk over the years has seen he has a larger vision in mind, and the Solar City acquisition positions Tesla closer to that goal than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expect we&amp;rsquo;ll see news of a larger charging station rollout, a bigger push into residential solar/battery installations, Solar City&amp;rsquo;s role in both of those, and perhaps an update on the Gigafactory and its ability to transform the already quickly changing battery market. Put together, Tesla would be positioned to play an incredibly powerful role in the transition to a green energy grid through a decentralized energy production and distribution system that relies heavily on energy arbitrage. The real clincher would be if stronger state partnerships have been worked out and an announcement of Tesla pursuing closer relationships with more states as a way to secure tax credits for consumers adopting Tesla/other green energy tech that fits with this model. Investors only ever see the short term dollars and cents after all, but I suspect the master plan will be grand indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;story: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/jul/10/elon-musk-tesla-twitter-top-secret-masterplan&#34;&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
