<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meta on recursivewit</title>
    <link>http://recursivew.it/meta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meta on recursivewit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 15:04:11 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://recursivew.it/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Tribalism: The Root Of All Evil, And Its Deterministic March Toward Dystopia</title>
      <link>http://recursivew.it/meta/tribalism-root-cause-evil-dystopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 15:04:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://recursivew.it/meta/tribalism-root-cause-evil-dystopia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The love of money is the root of all evil. - 1 Timothy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bunk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea that money is the root of all evil is one that permeates our culture. Its a phrase we&amp;rsquo;ve all heard repeated time and time again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oddly enough though, despite our acknowledgment that money has a dark side, as a society we elevate it to a god-like position. In god we trust indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the surface, it makes sense. Love of money is a form of greed, and greed can lead to many evils, so of course money must be the root of them all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there we pat ourselves on the back telling ourselves we&amp;rsquo;ve figured it out, and then go back to worshiping the same source of evil we&amp;rsquo;ve just identified. We externalize the problem, saying its money&amp;rsquo;s fault and clearly &lt;em&gt;we&amp;rsquo;re&lt;/em&gt; not guilty of the same greed that evil comes from, and we go on thinking we&amp;rsquo;re not contributing to the world&amp;rsquo;s evils and that a moneyless society would clearly be without its evils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surely when you break the idiom down in that way, where you imagine simply removing the claimed source of evil, it becomes clear how silly fingering money alone as the source of evil becomes. Money is an abstraction of power, and power exists with or without a currency. Evil will still exist regardless of money&amp;rsquo;s role in society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What then is the root of all evil? Evil is clearly a many faceted thing, but if there were to be a root it would seem to me that its certainly not the love of money, but instead tribalism that generates evil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of tribalism is built around the constructs of &lt;em&gt;in groups&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;out groups&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Haves&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;have nots&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;cool kids&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;losers&lt;/em&gt;. This innate sense of tribalism has served us well at many times in history when it was a necessary social survival mechanism. But like money it has a dark side, and given our evolution and social development we must unfortunately acknowledge that dark side is baked into our very core. We&amp;rsquo;re trained not only by our community and society to fall into these groups, but our brains are wired to associate ourselves with groups in this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking of the world in terms of in and out groups, rather than greedy and not greedy groups, it would seem clear we&amp;rsquo;re all the evil sinners who&amp;rsquo;ve made this world such a mess. Perhaps if we move past pointing our fingers outward and instead acknowledging the fault lies in each one of us, we could see the course correction we so desperately need&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edit:&lt;/em&gt; Never finished this piece, but wanted to post it anyway. I&amp;rsquo;ll be fleshing out the idea more now that ~8 crazy months has past since it was written.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Am I Here?</title>
      <link>http://recursivew.it/meta/why-am-i-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 03:00:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://recursivew.it/meta/why-am-i-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why are any of us here? Its a bit like asking what the meaning of life is. Maybe in the end its as meaningless a question, but I think its an important idea that many people will consider at many points in their life. Why do we exist? For what purpose to we consume our environment, create waste, and eventually die? Or is the truth that there is no purpose and all this time thinking about it is ultimately a frivolous waste of the little time we&amp;rsquo;re certainly uncertain we have?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes and no. All of it, and none of it, at once and never. The truth is we know nothing about the world that we haven&amp;rsquo;t experienced, whether corporeally or through reason or empathy, and that while some people&amp;rsquo;s experiences will overlap with a great many others, most experiences are unique in nature and in the end come to represent different worlds. Not just different perspectives of one world, but entirely distinct worlds. While our purpose within the macro, objective world may indeed be, and in fact likely is, completely meaningless and irrelevant, our purpose within our own world becomes one of the most important questions for people to answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the conundrum of the ontological self. The self is what it thinks of its world. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t know how to be anything but that, because its world is simply the aggregate of its unique experiences which inserts the self into the very core of its world. There is indeed a world beyond that of the self, but as an embedded actor in that world, the world of the self is no less real than its macro reality because its not actually distinct from it, but rather an active part of the macro evolution of our shared world. In that sense, while most daily actions may be driven by a robotic self interest determined by our world, ignorant of the many worlds floating around ones own, to ask &amp;ldquo;Why am I here?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;What is my purpose?&amp;rdquo; in the end is to instead acknowledge these many worlds and assess ones place among them. Its a question that stops to ponder the existence of other worlds, even if only other versions of our own, and in doing so forces us to think of those worlds as being less distinct from one another than we tend to. While searching for an objective meaning of life is an exercise in folly, searching for meaning in ones own life helps the self come to a sense of equilibrium with its environment as its driven to close the gaps between the ideal and the reality of its world. Or put another way, to ask the subjective question &amp;ldquo;Why Am I Here?&amp;rdquo; is to aim at reducing the barriers between the world of the self and the many worlds it interacts with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This crappy piece of the internet isn&amp;rsquo;t all that different, if any of that made enough sense to make a comparison from. This site ultimately serves no purpose against the grand scales of the internet. It knows nothing of that broader web but the words and links that find its way onto it. To the internet, this site is as meaningless as we are to the universe. However to this site, it has to ask the question &amp;ldquo;Why Am I Here?&amp;rdquo; because to not do so would be to relinquish itself to non-existence. It is here because it is here, and now its purpose is to parse its world and determine how to improve upon it. It is here to ponder the barriers between it and the many other worlds on the internet, shaping its shared world and being shaped by it at once. It is here to discover, create, and communicate. It is here for the same reasons we are. None. And all of them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
