<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on @recursivewit</title>
    <link>http://recursivew.it/tags/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on @recursivewit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 21:24:53 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://recursivew.it/tags/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>sourced.fm: Restructuring the Music Industry With Community Driven Social Capitalism</title>
      <link>http://recursivew.it/projects/sourced-fm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 21:24:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://recursivew.it/projects/sourced-fm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Video may have killed the radio star, but industrial money killed music. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t its first time doing it. My fear is that unless we rally behind something better, its not going to be the last either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is the aristocracy has always found its ways to co-opt music for commoditized profits and influence. Throughout the renaissance era this came through the patronage model as patrons sought to influence culture by playing patron to the arts, primarily in pursuit of increased esteem among peers in a time when culture was associated with class. Throughout history this same model has been employed by the church to use music as a tool in their oppressive brainwashing of the masses. In more recent times, we know this aristocracy as the industrial label model of music through which big moneyed interests invest in and commoditize music primarily to increase profits. In all these forms of bought out music, music is secondary to another primary driving force. And for good reason; music is innately secondary to its primary driving force because music is primarily an emotional language. This is what makes it such a powerful tool for shaping group thought, and why its been consistently exploited by those with influence to increase and maintain their influence throughout our history. Its also why its time we take it back. Without music of and for the commons, we can&amp;rsquo;t share &lt;em&gt;our&lt;/em&gt; messages, only consume the messages produced for us. The more stifled music is, the more stifled we all are by extension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the industrial label model of music, music is treated as a mass producible consumer good, and labels insert themselves into the equation as if they were any other company manufacturing and selling goods in any industry. The primary driving force in this model is the profits created from sale of their commodity, in this case music. The issue with this arises when one asks &amp;ldquo;What &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; Music?&amp;rdquo; After thoughtful introspective examination I think this question will lead many to be within the ballpark that music is primarily an emotional language. If this is the case, by treating music as a mass producible good, the result is that the messages this emotional language get used for will serve to prop up the culture of the status quo that has benefited the moneyed interests at the expense of the messages of those who the system harms. Because of music&amp;rsquo;s enormous influence on the culture and society its made for, this communication inequality serves as an enormous driver of socio-economic and cultural bubbles that burst more violently than they would if the channels of communication were flatter and more open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before moving on, the &lt;strong&gt;TL;DR:&lt;/strong&gt; is that communication inequality created by our commoditized, profit driven industrial music model amplifies socio-economic bubbles by silencing the underclass and propping up the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now many might not see music as quite as big a deal as I do in relation with our state of socio-economic and political affairs, but if we can agree that music plays a &lt;em&gt;noticably large&lt;/em&gt; role in influencing our culture and that the industrial label model of music is at the very least &lt;em&gt;a little predatory, self serving, profit driven, and flawed&lt;/em&gt;, I think its enough common ground to establish a new paradigm for serving music that functions better, even if we differ on the magnitude of indirect changes this transition will lead to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Circling back to what music is, if it is in fact an emotional language then we have to ask ourselves, what should that language be used to say? If we have a tool that can express our ideas and feelings more deeply than anything written or spoke, how &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; it be used and toward &lt;em&gt;what ends&lt;/em&gt; should it aim its sights? While I would never suggest that musicians &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; use music to adopt a common purpose, as doing so would subvert music&amp;rsquo;s purpose in the same way labels have, I would suggest that if lensed through the idea that we suffer from communication inequality between the commons and the moneyed interests, for right now music&amp;rsquo;s end should ideally be to close that gap and do it by sharing the musician and their community&amp;rsquo;s world through their music. Musicians of the future need not concern themselves with chasing commercial trends, or boasting about swag or fetishized objects, but should instead seek to return to the roots of what music is, and use it to give a voice to the voiceless, to laud the under-appreciated laudable things, and to rebuke the anachronistic cultural artifacts that its time we shed. Music is what we make it, and I believe its time to make it as an organic bottom up community rather than a top down hierarchy peddling consumer fetishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[To be continued&amp;hellip;]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first of many posts I will make exploring the reasons and motivations for &lt;a href=&#34;http://sourced.fm&#34;&gt;sourced.fm&lt;/a&gt;, an ethereal project with the enormous ambitions of restructuring the music industry. The goal of the project is to find a way to restructure its industry in a way that re-focuses music on its core relationship between creator and listener as opposed to the creator-label-everybodyelse model we rely on now. In this new model, all other actors are secondary to these core two, and as we&amp;rsquo;ll establish, by focusing the core of the industry on the creators and listeners, it becomes possible to establish a self sufficient model of music support that operates more efficiently than the one we&amp;rsquo;re used to. Through these efficiencies and focus on decentralizing and democratizing music, this model flattens the channels of communication, and by extension success. In this new model, profit is removed as a driving force by building atop a non-profit organization. In this new model, the communication of ideas through music is the primary driving force.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sourced.fm&lt;/strong&gt; aims to make music by the commons, for the commons a viable path for musicians to pursue without compromise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
