<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dystopia on recursivewit</title>
    <link>http://recursivew.it/tags/dystopia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dystopia on recursivewit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 15:04:11 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://recursivew.it/tags/dystopia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Tribalism: The Root Of All Evil, And Its Deterministic March Toward Dystopia</title>
      <link>http://recursivew.it/meta/tribalism-root-cause-evil-dystopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 15:04:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://recursivew.it/meta/tribalism-root-cause-evil-dystopia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The love of money is the root of all evil. - 1 Timothy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bunk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea that money is the root of all evil is one that permeates our culture. Its a phrase we&amp;rsquo;ve all heard repeated time and time again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oddly enough though, despite our acknowledgment that money has a dark side, as a society we elevate it to a god-like position. In god we trust indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the surface, it makes sense. Love of money is a form of greed, and greed can lead to many evils, so of course money must be the root of them all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there we pat ourselves on the back telling ourselves we&amp;rsquo;ve figured it out, and then go back to worshiping the same source of evil we&amp;rsquo;ve just identified. We externalize the problem, saying its money&amp;rsquo;s fault and clearly &lt;em&gt;we&amp;rsquo;re&lt;/em&gt; not guilty of the same greed that evil comes from, and we go on thinking we&amp;rsquo;re not contributing to the world&amp;rsquo;s evils and that a moneyless society would clearly be without its evils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surely when you break the idiom down in that way, where you imagine simply removing the claimed source of evil, it becomes clear how silly fingering money alone as the source of evil becomes. Money is an abstraction of power, and power exists with or without a currency. Evil will still exist regardless of money&amp;rsquo;s role in society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What then is the root of all evil? Evil is clearly a many faceted thing, but if there were to be a root it would seem to me that its certainly not the love of money, but instead tribalism that generates evil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of tribalism is built around the constructs of &lt;em&gt;in groups&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;out groups&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Haves&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;have nots&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;cool kids&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;losers&lt;/em&gt;. This innate sense of tribalism has served us well at many times in history when it was a necessary social survival mechanism. But like money it has a dark side, and given our evolution and social development we must unfortunately acknowledge that dark side is baked into our very core. We&amp;rsquo;re trained not only by our community and society to fall into these groups, but our brains are wired to associate ourselves with groups in this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking of the world in terms of in and out groups, rather than greedy and not greedy groups, it would seem clear we&amp;rsquo;re all the evil sinners who&amp;rsquo;ve made this world such a mess. Perhaps if we move past pointing our fingers outward and instead acknowledging the fault lies in each one of us, we could see the course correction we so desperately need&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edit:&lt;/em&gt; Never finished this piece, but wanted to post it anyway. I&amp;rsquo;ll be fleshing out the idea more now that ~8 crazy months has past since it was written.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
